Now, accuracy may not always be the best metric to use.
准确率并非始终是最佳指标
我们看一个示例
Let's look at this example.
该示例是检测信用卡欺诈行为
It consists of detecting credit card fraud.
So we have a bunch of data in the form of credit card transactions,
有一堆信用卡交易数据
有些数据是良好的数据 例如左侧的数据
and some of them are good like the ones on the left,
and some of them are fraudulent like the ones in the right.
有些是欺诈行为 例如右侧的数据
我们来看看数字
So let's look at the numbers.
There are 284,335 good transactions,
有 284,335 条良好的交易
和 472 条欺诈性交易
and 472 fraudulent transactions.
这其实是现实生活中的数据
This is actually real data.
我们试着找出一个准确率很高的模型
So let's try to come up with a model that has great accuracy.
即大部分时间都正确的模型
So a model that is correct most of the time.
能想到准确率超过 99% 的模型吗？
Can you help me think of a model that has over 99% accuracy?
So here's a model that has over 99% accuracy,
下面描述下准确率超过 99% 的模型
也就是超过 99% 的时间都正确
which means it is correct over 99% of the time.
模型说 所有交易都是良好的交易
The model says, all the transactions are good.
这个模型的准确率是多少
Now, what is the accuracy of this model namely,
即多少次是正确的？
how many times are we correct?
284,887 次中有 284,335 次是正确的
Well, we're correct 284,335 times out of 384,887 times.
结果是 99.83%
And that is 99.83%.
So this model must be pretty good if it's accurate that high, right?
所以这个模型肯定很不错 因为准确率如此的高 对吧？
实际并非这样 该模型没有发现任何不好的数据
Well, not really. This model is not catching any of the bad ones.
And the point of the model is to catch the fraudulent transactions.
模型的意义就是发现欺诈交易
So let's look at another model. To get a model that catches all the bad transactions.
我们再看看另一个模型 能获得发现所有欺诈交易的模型吗？
Can we think of one?
我们能想到一个吗？
Well here's one, I'm going to label all transactions fraudulent.
下面介绍一个 我将所有交易标记为欺诈行为
很棒了吧？我们发现了所有的欺诈交易
So that's great, right? Now we're catching
是好的模型吗？
all the fraudulent transactions. Now, is that a good model?
答案是否定的 也是一个糟糕的模型
Well, no that's also a terrible model since it's accidentally
catching all the good ones. So it's pretty tricky, right?
因为将所有好的交易也标记为欺诈交易 很棘手吧
仅通过准确率来评估模型比较棘手
It's pretty tricky to just look at accuracy and use that to evaluate our model,
because it may completely miss the point when the data is skewed like this one.
因为对于这样偏斜的数据集 可能会完全忽略一些点
So in this section, we'll study some different metrics that can catch this more easily.
在这部分 我们将学习一些不同的指标 可以更轻松地发现这类点